{"tossups": [{"question": "In 1908, Joseph Szombathy discovered a faceless depiction of this figure in the village of Willendorf. A Velazquez painting of this figure looking back at herself in a mirror was attacked by suffragette Mary Richardson. In another painting, this figure is blown by Zephyrus to shore and stands on a giant shell. An armless statue discovered on the island of Milos depicts, for ten points, what goddess whose birth is depicted in a painting by Sandro Botticelli?", "answer": "<b> Venus</b> (accept<b> Aphrodite</b>; accept<b> Venus</b> of Willendorf, Rokeby<b> Venus</b>,<b> Venus</b> de Milo, and/or Birth of<b> Venus</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "When observing Saturn, this scientist claimed to see two \u201cears\u201d that were later shown to be its rings. This author of<em> Two New Sciences</em> and<em> Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems</em> discovered the phases of Venus and the four largest moons of Jupiter, a set that he now names. For ten points, name this Italian scientist who was put under house arrest by the Roman Inquisition for professing the Copernican heliocentric theory.", "answer": "<b> Galileo Galilei</b> (accept either or both names)", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {"question": "This man formulated the \u201ceight-point regulation\u201d to make politicians \u201cdo real work\u201d and \u201csay real things.\u201d In<em> The Governance</em> of his country, this politician wrote about combating corruption as well as the Belt and Road Initiative. In 2018, this man spearheaded the removal of Presidential term limits from his country\u2019s constitution. Hu Jintao was succeeded by, for ten points, what current General Secretary of the Communist Party of China?", "answer": "<b> Xi</b> Jinping", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This ruler repudiated his marriage to Desiderata, the daughter of his rival Desiderius. A biography of this ruler by Einhard relates how he besieged and conquered Pavia, after which he took the title of King of the Lombards. Leo III urged this man to restore his authority from Roman conspirators, leading to his 800 AD coronation. For ten points, name this ruler of the Franks and Holy Roman Emperor.", "answer": "<b> Charlemagne</b> (accept<b> Charles I</b> or<b> Charles the Great</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This President\u2019s policies were opposed by the \u201cFour Horseman\u201d of the Supreme Court. Owen Robert\u2019s vote in<em> West Coast Hotel v. Parrish</em> to uphold one of this President\u2019s policies is referred to as the \u201cswitch in time that saved nine.\u201d This President treated to \u201cpack the court\u201d if it didn\u2019t support programs like the CCC and WPA. For ten points, name this President who tried to force the Supreme Court to support the New Deal.", "answer": "<b> F</b>ranklin Delano<b> Roosevelt</b> (accept<b> FDR</b>; prompt on Roosevelt)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man purged his rivals by using a North Korean-trained brigade that carried out the \u201crain that washes away the chaff.\u201d This man\u2019s downfall came when he removed Emmerson Mnangagwa from office, likely so he could name his wife Grace as Vice President. In 2000, land reforms by this African leader led to extreme hyperinflation. For ten points, name this head of the ZANU-PF who led Zimbabwe for 37 years.", "answer": "Robert<b> Mugabe</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In 2009, Herman Van Rompuy was made the first permanent head of a council directing this organization. This organization was established by the Maastricht Treaty which absorbed groups led by the \u201cInner Six\u201d and \u201cOuter Seven.\u201d In 2009, this organization passed the Treaty of Lisbon, which introduced Article 50 to its central document. The United Kingdom has attempted to leave, for ten points, what pan-national organization that includes countries like France and Germany?", "answer": "<b> European Union</b> (accept<b> EU</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In 1815, Henry Salt hired Giovanni Belzoni to secure a giant statue of this man, the Younger Memnon, from his memorial temple. This ruler ordered the creation of a temple complex at Abu Simbel, partially to honor his wife Nefertari. With Mursili III, this man signed the Eternal Treaty which was meant to end his conflict with the Hittites. For ten points, name this Egyptian pharaoh who won the Battle of Kadesh in 1259 BC.", "answer": "<b> Ramses II</b> (accept<b> Ramses the Great</b>; prompt on Ramses)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This novel was inspired by the author\u2019s summers with Truman Persons. The Scottsboro boys\u201d unfair trials inspired a scene in this novel in which Calpurnia sits with her employer\u2019s children while Mayella Ewell falsely accuses a man of rape. Dill Harris visits this novel\u2019s protagonists, who obsess over the reclusive Boo Radley while their father defends Tom Robinson. For ten points, name this novel about lawyer Atticus Finch and his children, Jem and Scout, written by Harper Lee.", "answer": "<b> To Kill a Mockingbird</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "During this war, Alvin York captured 132 soldiers leading a surprise attack on an enemy fortification. The \u201cLost Battalion\u201d became encircled by enemy troops during this war\u2019s Meuse-Argonne offensive. A document detailing a proposed German-Mexican alliance, the Zimmerman Telegram, was intercepted during this war. John Pershing led American troops nicknamed \u201cDoughboys\u201d in, for ten points, what war that the United States joined in 1917?", "answer": "<b> World War I</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man allied with France against the Ottoman Empire after his adviser, Cardinal Wolsey, signed the Treaty of London. Francis I met with this king at the Field of the Cloth of Gold. This man passed two Acts of Supremacy, making him the head of the newly formed Anglican Church, after the Pope refused to annul his marriage to Catherine of Aragon. For ten points, name this King of England, the father of Elizabeth I and husband to six wives.", "answer": "<b> Henry VIII</b> (prompt on Henry)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This actor plays a man who serves under Colonel Bagley and is given a salary of $500 a month by Omura to help Emperor Meiji destroy a class of swordsmen. In another film, this man plays a character who is tasked with carrying out an attack with a pencil detonator at the Wolf\u2019s Lair. This actor, who starred in<em> The Last Samurai</em> and played Colonel Stauffenberg in 2008\u2019s<em> Valkyrie</em>, has been criticized in Europe for advertising a cult. For ten points, name this prominent Scientologist and star of the<em> Mission:</em> <em>Impossible</em> series.", "answer": "Tom<b> Cruise</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This thinker claimed that a government ruled by \u201ccrowned ruffians\u201d would always result in \u201cblood and ashes\u201d in the book</b><em><b> Agrarian Justice</b></em><b>. This thinker responded to Edmund Burke\u2019s</b><em><b> Reflections on the Revolution in France</b></em><b> in the book (+)</b><em><b> Rights of Man</b></em><b> and claimed</b> <b>that it was absurd that an island could rule a (*)</b> continent in one of his pamphlets urging for American Independence. For ten points, name this author of<em> The American Crisis</em> and \u201cCommon Sense.\u201d", "answer": "Thomas<b> Paine</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This man\u2019s foreign minister was assassinated by a Buddhist preacher in the League of Blood Incident. In the Kyujo Incident, a group of generals attempted to force this man into</b> <b>house arrest before he could (+)</b> <b>address the nation. This man announced his acceptance</b> <b>of the Joint Declaration of Powers in the Jewel Voice Broadcast. After his nation (*) </b>surrendered aboard the USS<em> Missouri</em>, this man was forced to renounce his divinity. For ten points, name this Emperor of Japan during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Hirohito</b> (accept<b> Showa</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A ruler with this name adopted the surname \u201cMikhailov\u201d before meeting with William III and traveling through Western Europe, but his tall stature made it hard to go completely</b> <b>unnoticed during his \u201cGrand (+)</b> <b>unnoticed during his \u201cGrand (+)</b> <b>Embassy.\u201d The first ruler with this name imposed a tax</b> <b>on the (*)</b> beards of the Boyars as part of his efforts to modernize Russia. For ten points, name this beards of the Boyars as part of his efforts to modernize Russia. For ten points, name this \u201cgreat\u201d Russian tsar who established a large port city on the Baltic Sea.", "answer": "<b> Peter</b> the Great (or<b> Peter</b> I)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Eugenics research was once carried out at what is now this island\u2019s Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory. In an August 1776 battle, fighting took place on this island at the Rockaway</b> <b>Foot Path and Jamaica Pass. The first (+)</b> <b>Levittown was created in this island\u2019s Nassau</b> <b>County. The 1938 New England Hurricane destroyed dozens of seaside estates in the (*) </b>Hamptons on this island. A namesake sound separates Connecticut from, for ten points, what island that is home to Queens and Brooklyn?", "answer": "<b> Long</b> Island", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>Sarah Bradford wrote a book titled</b><em><b> Scenes in the Life</b></em><b> of this woman and returned all the proceeds to fund her activism. While serving as a scout under James (+) Montgomery, this woman led a successful raid on Combahee Ferry. This woman was asked to participate in an attack on a (*) </b> Virginia armory by an abolitionist, but was too sick to attend. For ten points, name this woman nicknamed \u201cMoses\u201d who \u201cnever lost a passenger\u201d while helping slaves escape on the Underground Railroad.", "answer": "Harriet<b> Tubman</b> (accept Araminta<b> Ross</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>These weapons were first organized into a corps by Samuel Rockenbach, who used the foreign Star variant heavily in the Meuse-Argonne offensive. During World War</b> <b>II, the Locust and (+)</b> <b>Hellcat were designed to replace the Stuart \u201clight\u201d type of</b> <b>Hellcat were designed to replace the Stuart \u201clight\u201d type of</b> <b>these vehicles. Iconic American examples of these vehicles include the (*)</b> <b>these vehicles. Iconic American examples of these vehicles include the (*)</b> Sherman and the M1 Abrams. For ten points, name these heavily armored and turreted vehicles.", "answer": "<b> tank</b>s (accept any specific type, such as Star<b> tank</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}